aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
Sky! Earth! Human!
천(天)! 지(地)! 인(人)!
Gather the three principle into one!
3가지의 이치(理)를 하나로 모아!
This is Dag Shadow! Absolute Light Speed Sword!
이것이 다그 섀도우! 절대 광속검!!
Shadow Dragon!
섀도우 드래곤!
Dragon Plasma Burn!
드래곤 플라즈마 번!!
You did it! That's an additional specialty!
해냈구만! 이걸로 특기가 하나 더 늘었군
Ryu!
류!!
-Hey! Hang in there!
-Ryu!
-이봐! 정신차리라구!
-류!!
D- don't worry. It's alright now.
괘, 괜찮아... 걱정하지마
It vanished.
녀석은 소멸했다
It was its last struggle.
최후의.. 발버둥이었어...
Ryu!
류!
Hey! Hey, Ryu! Wake up!
이봐! 이봐, 류! 정신차려!!
The Mystery of Sargasso
사르갓소의 수수께끼
Prison Guard Robot Guardroid
Appears
간수 로봇 가드로이드 등장
Seems that the wound wasn't too big.
몸의 상처는 심하지 않았던 것 같습니다
His health is only to be restored.
남은건 체력만 회복하면...
I... I...
나, 난...
I...
난...
Ryu, don't move yet.
류, 아직 움직이지 마라
I saw.
난 봤어
Saw? Saw what?
봤다고? 대체 뭘!?
Sargasso, the Space Prison.
우주감옥 사르갓소
Get a grip. That probably was a dream.
정신차려, 꿈이라도 꾼 거겠지
No. That light.
아니야, 그 빛
Right in the moment of crashing with Chaois Seijin, I saw.
카오스 성인과 격돌한 순간 난 봤어
Chaois Seijin is a spiritual life-form without a body.
카오스 성인은 육체를 가지지 않은 정신 생명체로
Instead of having a body, it can possess anything.
육체 대신에 녀석은 온갖 물체와 동화하는 능력이 있어
How do you know that?
어떻게 그런 걸 알고 있지?
I guess it tried to merge the spirits.
분명히, 정신 융합일 겁니다
-Merge the spirits?
-Yes.
-정신 융합?
-네
It's just a short moment of collision, but they became one and Chaos Seijin's memory went into Ryu's head.
격돌했을 때 한순간이지만 둘은 동화되어 카오스 성인의 기억이 류의 머리 속으로..
Sargasso, the Space Prison.
우주감옥 사르갓소
That was built to imprison the vicious criminals.
그건 흉악한 우주 범죄자를 수용할 목적으로 건조된 거야
It imprisoned its prisoners using artificial black holes.
인공적으로 만들어낸 기지 블랙홀로 죄수들을 감금하고
It was an inescapable space prison managed by a strict guard system.
엄중한 경비 시스템으로 관리되는 탈옥 불가능한 우주감옥이었어
But a day, a space storm sizing about the solar system directly hit Sargasso.
그런데, 어느날 태양계 규모의 우주 폭풍이 사르갓소를 직격
By this, more than 5000 prisoners managed to get out of artificial black holes and took the control of Sargasso.
이걸 계기로 5000명이 넘는 죄수들은 기지 블랙홀의 속박을 빠져나와, 사르갓소를 점령한 거야
To them, invasion is like a game.
녀석들에게 있어 침략은 게임이야
They are bloodthirsty hunters who are aiming for the prey named the Earth.
녀석들은 지구라는 이름의 먹이를 노리는 피에 굶주린 사냥꾼이야
More than 5000 of Sargasso's prisoners...
5000명이 넘는 사르갓소의 죄수들
More than 5000 test subjects!
연구재료가 5000개!
Even if we take down one a day, it will take more than 13 years...
하루에 한마리씩 해치운다고 해도 13년 이상
Will I ever have a time to date?
데이트 할 틈은 없는 건가 -_-;;
Hey, En!
이봐, 엔!
What is it? Why would you call us in this deep night?
대체 무슨 일이야?
이런 한밤중에 불러내고 말야
I have an important research remaining...
전 중요한 연구가 남아있습니다만
This is the reason I called you.
두사람을 부른건 다른게 아니야
Did you hear that Ryu was around the school late time after the school?
방과후 늦은 시간에 류의 모습을 봤다는 이야기 했지?
The students doing club activities saw him numerous time, if I recall.
부 활동하던 학생들이 몇번이고 목격했었다던 이야기 말입니까?
There was one who saw him in my club too.
우리 부에도 본 녀석이 있었지
Yeah, he definitely went up back to the mountain.
분명히, 뒷산 쪽으로 올라갔다던가
That's it! That.
그거야 그거
I investigated about Ryu recently, but I couldn't find out anything about him. Including his address.
내가 최근에 류에 대해 조사해 봤는데 녀석에 대해선 뭐 하나 알아낼 수 없었어, 주소마저 말야
So?
그래서?
So I thought.
그래서 난 생각했어
Ryu lives in the mountain back of the school!
류는 학교 뒷산에서 살고 있다!
Do you really think so?
정말 그렇게 생각하고 계신 겁니까?
So we're going to find that out!
그러니까 그걸 확인하러 가는거야
Don't say stupid! He's not a mountain man,
바보같은 소리 마! 산신령도 아니고
and do you think there'll be someone living in a tent on the mountain nowadays?
요즘 세상에 산에 천막치고 사는 녀석이 있을 것 같냐!?
I am not going.
난 안갈거야
I see...
그래...
So won't you care even if your friend is living poorly in a mountain?
동료가 산 속에서 불우한 생활을 하고 있어도 신경 안쓴다는 거냐
So our Dagwon's friendship wasn't deep at all?
우리들 다그온의 우정은 별로 두텁지도 않았구나
Hey, just a moment, En!
이봐, 기다려 엔
Okay, I get it! Let's go, Yoku.
알았어, 알았다구!
가자, 요쿠
He thinks about his friends more than I thought!
저녀석 의외로 친구 걱정 많이 하는구만
I think it's just a curiosity.
단순한 호기심이라고 생각합니다만
-Hey, if you decided to go, then go!
-Hey, don't push!
-자, 자 갈거면 얼른 가자구!
-이봐! 밀지 말라구!
That's as far as you go!
거기까지다!
Don't let go so suddenly!
아악! 갑자기 손 놓지 말라구! 아아악~!!
Entering the school when the door is closed is forbidden.
폐문(閉門)일 때 허가 없이 교내로 들어가는 것은 금지되어 있다
W- wait, Kai! We were just trying to check if Ryu...
기, 기다려 카이! 우리들은 류를..
Don't say! 4 or 5!
But if the rumor is true and Ryu is staying in the school without permission,
하지만 만에하나 소문이 사실이며 류가 무단으로 학교 내에서 숙박하고 있다면
I am obliged to regulate him for being the chief of disciplines!
난 풍기위원장으로서 녀석을 단속할 의무가 있다!
Why did he take a lamp?
왜 저녀석이 손전등 같은걸 가지고 있는거야?
I guess he was going to follow us after all.
처음부터 저럴 생각이었겠죠
-What's wrong?
-Someone's comming!
-왜그래?
-누군가 온다!
Someone?
누군가라니
I don't know. I sensed somebody's presence, but it's too dark.
모르겠어, 기척은 느꼈지만 이렇게 어두워서야
Leave it to me. I thought this might happen, so I took this.
제게 맡겨 주세요 "이런 일도 있을 것 같아서" 이걸 가져왔습니다
What?
뭐야~?
You too were going to follow me after all?
결국 너도 그럴 생각이었단 거구만
-It's Asahiyama principal!
-Huh? Grandpa?
-아사히야마 교장 선생님입니다
-에에? 할아버지?
It's a good night. Truly a good night.
좋은 밤이야, 정말 좋은 밤이야
It's a stupendous night that I can listen to the voice of the Earth.
이렇게 지구의 목소리를 귀를 기울일 수 있는 정말 좋은 밤이야
But gentlemen, please go back as soon as possible.
하지만 제군들!
되도록 빨리 돌아가세요
You might catch a cold.
감기 걸리니까 말이예요
He knows...
알고 계셔...
Hey, are we sure that we are still inside the school?!
이봐~ 이봐
여기 정말 학교 안(中) 맞아?
I can't do this anymore.
더이상은 안되겠어
Let's divide for today.
오늘은 이쯤에서 찢어지자구
It's not even a warming up.
겨우 이정도론 준비운동도 안돼
Who's there?!
누구냐!?
-Who was that?!
-Yoku.                         -Got it.
-지금 그건?!
-요쿠                         -네
It's too fast to find out!
너무 빨라서 확인할 수 없습니다
-Let's follow!
-Roger!
-쫓아가자!
-알았어!
-Hey, wait!
-Wait for us, Ryu!
이봐, 기다려!
기다리라구, 류!
-Huh?
-I'm sure he went this way.
-어레?
-확실히 이쪽으로 갔을텐데
Look at that!
저걸 보세요!
Inside there?
저 안인가
Great!
좋아!
No way! I never knew something like this would be on the mountain back of the school.
말도안돼! 학교 뒷산에 이런게!?
What a beautiful stalactite cavern!
훌륭한 종유동이군요
Right. It's truly the art of the mother nature.
그래. 정말로 대자연의 예술이군
If there was a hot spring here, it would be a perfect spot for tourists.
여기에 온천이라도 껴있으면 멋진 관광지겠구만
Heh, mixed bathing!
으흐흐.. 혼욕이다, 혼욕 -_-;;
What's wrong?
왜그래?
I see a light in front of us.
전방에 빛이 보입니다
That must be Ryu's house! No doubt about it!
저곳이야말로 류의 집이다!
틀림없다구!!
What the heck is this?
대체 뭐지, 이건!?
Look! That's Fire Jumbo!
봐! 저거, 파이어 점보라구!!
But why are they here?
하지만 어째서 이곳에?
-Don't you guys get it?
-Get what?
-너희들, 아직도 모르겠냐?
-뭘 말야?
This is our base!
이건 우리들의 기지라구!!
Our base?
우리들의 기지?
Brave Seijin made this for us!
분명히 브레이브 성인이 준비해 둔거야!
It's the base of Dagwon!
다그온의 기지라구!
Your machines are in maintenance.
너희들의 머신이 수리받고 있어
Yeah, the equipment here is awesome!
아아! 왠지 대단한 설비구만
-Is it Ryu?
-I guess so.
-역시 류인가
-그렇겠죠
What is it about?
무슨 소리야?
The shadow we saw before is Ryu.
아까 본 사람 그림자는 류야
He was there to guide us to here.
우리들을 이곳으로 안내하기 위해 녀석은 모습을 보인거야
Then does that mean Ryu knew about this Base all the time?
그럼 류 녀석, 이 기지를 알고 있었단 말야?
If then, why did he tell us earlier?
그럼 왜 빨리 이야기해 주지 않은거야!?
If he told about this, wouldn't this place be revealed to others in the school?
이걸 이야기하면 학교 사람들에게 들켜버리잖습니까?
Damn guy! He kept this to his own secret!
이녀석! 자기만 이런 비밀을 알고 있다니 말야!
-It's me.
-Ryu!
-나다
-류!
Where are you? Come here right now!
지금 어디야? 얼른 이리로 와!
-It seems that there are no time for that.
-What?!
-그럴 틈은 없는 것 같다
-뭐라고!?
Big disks appeared in the village.
마을에 거대한 원반이 나타났다
What's that?!
뭐야 저건!?
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Shadow Ryu Shuriken!
섀도우 류 수리검!
Dance of Insanity!
핫쿄우의 춤!!
Ryu!
류!!
류!
Who are they?!
이녀석들은!?
Guardroid, the prison guard robots of Sargasso!
가드로이드, 사르갓소의 간수 로봇이다!
What?!
뭐야!?
Seems that they are being controlled by someone.
아무래도 누군가에게 조종당하고 잇는 것 같아
-Shoulder Burn!
-Shadow Kunai!
-숄더 번!!
-섀도우 쿠나이!!
-That's it!
-Up to you, Shin!
-저겁니다!
-좋아! 부탁한다 신!
Leave it to me!
맡겨 두라구!
Seems that they had no time for counterattack.
반격할 틈도 없었던 것 같구만
It's not working at all!
전혀 듣질 않잖아!?
Wh- what's that?!
뭐, 뭐지 저건!?
-We did it!
-The remaining is...
-해치웠다!
-남은건...
Wh- what the?!
뭐, 뭐야!?
That's a... black hole!
저건.. 블랙홀!
-Black hole?
-Everyone! Get away from that!
-블랙홀!?
-얘들아! 그녀석에게서 떨어져!
What?!
뭐라고!?
Ryu!
류!!
Shadow Jet!
섀도우 제트!!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!!
Dag Fire!
다그 파이어!!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!!
Dag Shadow!
다그 섀도우!!
I'll attack from front!
난 정면에서 공격할게!
You watch and attack from behind!
틈을 봐서 넌 뒤에서 공격해!
Got it!
알았어!
Star Burn!
스타 번!!
Alright then! Fire Blaster!
좋아! 그렇다면!
파이어 블래스터!!
It's not working!
큭! 안되는군!
What the-?!
아니!?
Dag Shadow!
다그 섀도우!!
What?!
아니!?
You bastard! Do not underestimate me!
이자식! 얕보지 말라구!
Do not play with us!
날 가지고 노는구만!
Shadow Dragon!
섀도우 드래곤!
Dragon Plasma Burn!
드래곤 플라즈마 번!!
What the-?!
아니!?
That's enough, you punk!
이자식! 잘도 나댔겠다!!
Da- Dag Fire!
다, 다그 파이어!!
Yo- you guys!
너, 너희들!
Co- combine?!
하, 합체라고!?
Alright! Mecha-beast Fusion!
좋아! 기수합체(機獸合體)!!
That is...
저건!?
Could it be?
설마!?
Shadow Dagwon!
섀도우 다그온!!
I, Shadow Dagwon, will face you this time!
이번엔 이 섀도우 다그온이 상대해 주마!!
Sh- Shadow Dagwon?!
섀, 섀도우 다그온!?
Shadow Cannon!
섀도우 캐논!!
Finish!
마지막이다!!
The way of the spirit, the Kagemurasaki! (Purple Shadow)
명도 카게 무라사키(名刀影紫)!!
Shadow Beast King Slash!
섀도우 아왕참(我王斬り)!!
We did it!
해치웠다!
That was awesome, Ryu! You are now able to combine with those three Shadow Guards!
대단해, 류! 그 3체의 섀도우 가드와 합체할 수 있게 되었다니 말야
I guess so.
뭐, 그렇지
Anyway, it seems that there is somebody wandering in the school without permission in the night.
그건 그렇고, 한밤중에 무단으로 교내를 배회하는 자가 있다는 것 같다
Well, thanks to that guy, we could find the base of Dagwon.
그녀석 덕에 우리들은 다그온의 기지를 발견할 수 있었지만 말야
And?
그래서?
-Huh? You aren't surprised about the base?
-Just as we expected.
-얼레? 기지에 대해 듣고 안 놀라냐?
-역시군요
Get to the point.
무슨 말을 하고 싶은거냐?
You can tell us now, you bratty bratty brat!
이제 그만 불란 말이다.
요놈 요놈 요놈아!
Who the heck are you?!
누구냐, 네놈은!?
I am Ark Seijin.
난 아크 성인
Ark Seijin?!
아크 성인!?
Were you controlling those Guardroids?
네녀석이 가드로이드를 조종하고 있었던 거냐!?
This is merely a greetings.
이번 것은 인사치례일 뿐
I look forwards to meet you again, Dagwon gentlemen!
다음에 만날 날을 기대하고 있도록, 다그온 제군!
Ark Seijin!
아크 성인!!
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
tomaru koto nai MELODY
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
tooku kirameita
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
kaze no naka no PRISM
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
It's so sleepy!
졸려~ 졸려~
By the sudden sleepiness that crept over, no matter how school and village are, nap time!
갑자기 닥쳐온 강력한 졸음에 마을이고 학교고 모두 안녕히 주무세요~
Among them, a member of Dagwon, Kai Hirose was struggling!
그 가운데 혼자서 분투하는 다그온의 한명, 히로세 카이!
What?! The reason if Space Beast Mognel?!
뭐야!? 원인은 우주수 모그넬!?
Don't make us laugh! We Dagwon yawn~
웃기지 마라! 우리들 다그온은 아하~암
No good. I'm too sleepy to do anything.
안되겠어~ 졸려서 힘이 안나와~
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! A Dangerous Sleep
다음회 용자지령 다그온
위험한 잠
I entrust you, chief of disciplines!
부탁한다, 풍기위원장!!
A Dangerous Sleep
위험한 잠